I need to use the restroom.
我要上厕所
Can't you understand me?
你们俩听不懂我说话吗
Find a spot to pull over.
前面找地儿停车
Do you have to watch me pee?
撒尿都还要盯着呀
Mr... Mr. Hua...
华 华先生
Get out!
下来
Please
华先生
don't make this difficult.
不要为难我们
Mr...
华
Thinking of running?
还想跑啊
Can you even escape?
跑得了吗
How was it in the cold storage?
在冷库的滋味不好受吧
Tell me,
说说吧
where is Mr. Peng and his wife?
姓彭的和他老婆在哪儿
What exactly does Xiang Yuansheng
向远生救他们
plan to do by saving them?
到底想干什么
But what's plan by catching them?
那你抓他们想要干什么
I've told you,
我告诉过你了
Peng is a murderer.
彭记者是杀人犯
As a cop,
我是警察
it's my duty to arrest him.
逮捕他天经地义
This isn't an arrest.
这不是逮捕
But a kidnapping.
是绑架
That day you pretended to be his wife
那天你假扮记者老婆
to play a scene with Xiang Yuansheng,
跟向远生演戏
and you had an accomplice
你们还有个同伙
who took him away.
把记者带走了
Who was it?
他是谁
Bai Shoujun?
白守俊
Tian Dongbao?
田冬宝
Sun Hongfa?
孙鸿发
Or Chen Hao?
还是陈浩
The Fourth Station has been disbanded.
四所都已经撤了
Why do you guys
你们这帮人为什么
still stick together
每天还勾结在一起
like bad omens?
阴魂不散
Why did Tian Dongbao's wife run?
田冬宝老婆为什么要跑
What shameful things
她跟你说什么
did she tell you?
见不得人的事儿了
Didn't I tell you,
我不是跟你说了吗
we're just talking about cooking.
我们在聊做饭的事
You want to hear that too?
你也想听
I'm giving you one last chance.
我再给你最后一次机会
Call Xiang Yuansheng,
打电话给向远生
and tell him to come to
让他来水产公司
the seafood company to replace you!
你们一个人换一个人
He's not in Shanghai.
他不在上海
Then call the S.M.C.!
那就打电话给电雷学校
If he wants to,
只要他想来
he can come from anywhere.
天南海北他都能来
I need him to admit personally
我要让他亲口承认
that he's hiding
是他把记者两口子
the journalist couple.
藏起来了
It's time for him to know
他得知道
that his brother
别以为他姓华
and the surname
他哥哥华梁替他撑腰
can't protect him from doing anything
他就能想干吗就干吗
and treat me like a fool!
就能拿我当猴耍
He has to hand them over!
他必须把人给我交出来
He's not in Shanghai,
他不在上海
and he's not coming.
他也不会来的
Either he comes,
要么他来换你
or you go back to the cold storage.
要么你继续回冰库
If you go back,
你回去
it won't be long before there's just
这地方大不了过两天
another female corpse.
多一具女尸
Just stuff it in a barrel,
往桶里 一塞
throw it into the sea,
扔到海里
and you'll disappear
你就从这个世界上
from this world.
消失了
Xiang Yuansheng is different from you.
向远生他跟你不一样
His name is Hua Zhen.
他叫华桢
He has background.
他有护身符
Just call him here.
你把他叫来
I'm just going to scare him.
我就是吓唬吓唬他
What are you afraid of?
你怕什么
He won't die here.
他不会死在这儿
But you're different.
但是你不一样
Killing you
弄死你
is like stepping on an ant,
就跟踩死一只蚂蚁一样
and no one will even glance down.
没有人会低头看一眼
Once you go in there,
这趟进去
there's no coming out for you.
你就不可能再出来了
Think carefully.
想好了
Yuansheng!
向警官
Is Minmin home?
珉敏在家吗
She's not.
珉敏不在家
Something might happen.
应该是出事儿了
We haven't told her family yet.
我们没敢跟她家里人说
What exactly happened?
到底什么情况
Minmin went to meet Yu.
珉敏去找小玉
Suddenly, a few men appeared
突然出现几个男的
and tried to capture them.
要抓她们
She helped Yu escape,
她帮小玉逃了
but she didn't get away herself.
她自己却没逃掉
Dongbao might be in trouble too.
冬宝可能也出事儿了
He hasn't come home yet,
他到现在都没回家
and I don't know if it's related
不知道跟那几个人
to those men.
有没有关系
Do you have any clues
你们还有没有什么
about those men?
关于那几个人的线索
I...
我 我想起来
They...
他
seemed
他们好像
to have come from a truck.
是从货车上面下来的
Was that truck unlicensed?
那货车是不是没有牌照
Yes... it seemed to be.
好 好像是没有
I understand now.
我知道什么情况了
They work for Feng Guangyun.
他们是冯广云的人
We'll go with you.
我们跟你一起去
Yu, you shouldn't come.
小玉你别去了 太危险
But you can't go home now either.
但是你现在不能回家
Do you have somewhere else to go?
你还有别的地方去吗
I have relatives
有一个亲戚
in a rural part of Songjiang District.
在松江乡下老家
Then head there first.
那你先回去
Don't come back
没有我们的消息
without hearing from us.
千万不要回来
We'll also find Dongbao.
我们也会找到冬宝的
Get in!
上车
Be careful.
小心
Don't do anything stupid!
老实点儿
Looks like quite a few people there.
看样子人不少啊
Could Minmin be inside?
珉敏有可能在里面吗
Last time here,
上次我和陈浩来的时候
there were only two workers.
里面只有两个工人
It's clearly more this time,
这次明显变多了
probably to
应该是为了
guard Luo Minmin.
看住骆珉敏的
Aren't we understaffed
咱这么直接进去
to just walk in?
人不够吧
No more work,
老张 大巩
come play mahjong!
别干了 快来打麻将了
Right away.
好嘞
Hurry up!
快点儿
Erbai,
二白
can you drive this car?
这车你能开吗
Yes.
能
Good.
好
Let's split up.
我们分头行动
Nine bamboos.
九条
Five characters.
五万
Pong.
碰
Two characters.
二万
Nine bamboos.
九条
Pong.
碰
Stop dawdling!
快啊
Six characters.
六万
Red dragon.
红中
Five characters.
五万
Five characters, pong.
五万 碰
Smash it!
砸呀
Quick!
快呀
Get inside!
往里躲呀你
How many people are here?
这是来了多少人啊
Stop! Run!
别砸了 跑啊
I haven't finished yet!
没扔完呢 哥
After them!
给我追
Why isn't it starting?
怎么还不着啊哥
Don't panic!
别慌
There you go.
着了
Come on!
快走
You five chase them by car!
你们五个人 开车去追
Yes!
是 是
Hurry!
快点儿
Move!
快
Everyone
今儿晚上
stay sharp tonight!
一个个都给我精神点儿
Where is Luo Minmin?
骆珉敏在哪儿
Where is she?
她在哪儿
Quick!
快快快
Someone's broken in!
进来人了
Hello, Mr. Feng,
喂 冯哥
someone has shown up.
有人找到水产公司来了
Is it Xiang Yuansheng?
是向远生
Not sure yet.
我还不清楚
What if it's him?
如果是他呢
Capture him directly!
直接抓
I need him to settle scores
我要拿他跟华梁
with Hua Liang.
讨个说法
Use whatever necessary
不管用什么办法
to hold him.
一定把人给我拖住
I'm on my way with backup.
我马上带人过去
Understood.
好 收到
Group one,
一组的人
go to the armory to get weapons.
马上去武器科领枪
Come with me.
跟我去三洋水产
Yes!
是
Is it the gas station
远生说的
Yuansheng mentioned?
是这个加油站吗
Yes.
是
They've followed us here.
他们跟过来了
Just like he said,
按他说的
we'll draw them away
我们把人引走
and leave the car for him.
把车给他留下
Okay.
好
Let's move!
走
Dongbao.
冬宝
Tian Dongbao...
田冬宝
Help!
来人啊
Is anyone there?
有没有人
Help!
快来人啊
Stop!
站住
You're here for the keys, right?
你是来找钥匙的吧
Don't bother,
别白费工夫了
I have them.
其实钥匙在我这儿
I knew you'd come
我知道你会来
for Luo Minmin.
救骆珉敏的
Mr. Feng has already told me...
冯哥已经给我交代了
Minmin.
珉敏
Are you okay?
你没事儿吧
Are you alright?
你还好吗
Dongbao...
冬宝
He...
冬宝他
Secure the perimeter.
把这儿给我围住
Don't let anyone go!
一个人都别放走
Hold your fire
都先别开枪
until I give the order.
等我指令
I want Xiang Yuansheng alive.
向远生我要活的
Yes, sir!
是
Gunshots there.
科长 枪声
Is it Xiang Yuansheng?
是向远生吗
Yes.
是
Hua Zhen!
华桢
The reporter you took away
你之前带走的彭记者
is a murderer!
是一桩谋杀案的凶手
You're not only
你现在不光
obstructing police work
阻碍警察办案
but harboring a criminal.
还在包庇犯人
You could be considered an accomplice,
我可以认为你是同犯
and we have you surrounded!
你已经被警察包围了
Are you alright?
没事儿吧
You're now resisting arrest with violence!
你现在是暴力拒捕
Minmin!
珉敏
This is your last chance!
我再给你最后一次机会
Hand over your weapon,
把枪交出来
or I am authorized
否则我可以
to order them to shoot!
命令对你开枪
Load your guns!
子弹都给我上膛
Mr. Feng,
冯哥
why did you shoot at Hua Zhen?
你怎么朝华桢开枪了呀
If he gets shot,
这他要是中枪了
things could get pretty ugly.
事情会闹大了呀
There's a body discovered.
三洋水产发现一具尸体
Seal off the area
马上封锁现场
and call in forensic services now.
安排法医过来鉴定
Yes!
是
Also,
另外
the suspect might be
凶手很可能就在
among those
刚才逃跑的
who just fled.
这几个人里头
Send out alerts
马上给
to clinics,
诊所
hospitals,
医院
and pharmacies immediately.
还有药店发协查通知
Anyone with gunshot wounds
一旦发现有中枪的人
or seeking anti-inflammatories
或者来买枪伤药
or frostbite treatments for gun wounds
消炎药和冻伤药的
must be reported!
马上报警
Copy that!
是
Follow me!
你们跟我来
Yes!
走
Come on.
来
Chen Hao!
陈浩
I've been shot.
中了一枪
How is Minmin?
珉敏怎么样
Hypothermia.
可能是失温
She was in that cold storage
她被关在我们之前
we visited before
去过那个冰库
for too long.
太久了
Make sure to keep her warm.
记得给她保暖
You need to stop the bleeding.
你现在需要止血
Chen Hao!
陈浩
Sir,
老板
do you have any antibiotics?
有消炎药吗
What do you need?
你要什么
Sulfanilamide powder.
磺胺粉
I don't have that.
这个没有
Sulfanilamide is ridiculously expensive now.
磺胺现在都什么天价了
How about alcohol and saline?
那酒精和生理盐水有吗
I have.
这个有
Also need some frostbite medicine,
还要一些冻伤药
bandages, gauze.
绷带 纱布
Frostbite medicine.
冻伤药
Gauze.
纱布
I have
能消毒的草药
other disinfectants
我这儿倒是有一些
available, like...
什么独一味啊 百宝丹
Give them
要要要 我都要
anything antiseptic!
只要是能消毒的我都要
Take this money and give me
这些钱能拿多少东西
whatever it can buy.
你都给我拿过来
Okay.
好
Sir,
老板
do you know where
你知道到哪
I might still be able to buy sulfanilamide?
还能买到磺胺粉吗
It's more expensive than gold right now.
磺胺现在比黄金都贵
You won't easily find it even in big clinics
你就去大诊所 黑医院
or back-alley hospitals.
都不见得有
But if you really want it,
不过你要真想要
I could try to get it for you,
我可以去黑市上帮你买
though it won't be cheap
不过价钱可是不便宜
and
而且
you'd have to
你还得
pay me for the trouble.
给我点儿跑腿费不是
This watch
我这块表
is quite valuable.
值不少钱
Could you make a run for me?
拜托你帮我跑一趟
Sure,
行
come back tomorrow morning.
你明天上午来拿
Okay.
好
Sir,
老板
with this watch,
我能拿这只表
can I also trade for a blanket
再换一块毛毯
and some food?
和一些吃的吗
Take whatever you need.
你能看上你就拿
Thank you.
谢谢
Captain!
队长
You're awake.
醒了
Here,
来
you need to keep warm.
你现在需要保暖
What about Captain?
队长呢
How's he doing?
他怎么样了
He's been shot.
他中了一枪
The bullet went from his back to his chest.
子弹从后背到前胸贯穿
Fortunately, it didn't hit
幸好没有伤到
any major blood vessels
重要的血管
or organs,
和内脏器官
so there's no heavy bleeding.
没有大出血
I've managed to stop the bleeding.
我已经给他止血了
Chen Hao,
陈浩
don't move yet.
先别动
Captain...
队长
The bullet went straight through.
子弹贯穿了
We can't go to the hospital or clinics
医院和诊所都有警察
due to the police there.
暂时去不了
There's no sulfanilamide available.
药店又没有磺胺粉
All I can do is to stop
我只好给你做了
the bleeding and disinfect the wound.
基础的止血和消毒
I'll make it through.
我能扛过去
I've always been lucky.
我运气一直都很好
Are you alright?
你还好吗
What's wrong,
没事儿吧
kiddo?
小丫头
Why are you crying?
怎么还哭了
Bad news awaiting?
是谁出事了吗
You just got your life back.
你刚捡回一条命
We'll talk tomorrow.
明天再说吧
Tell me now.
现在说
Should I start guessing names?
要我一个一个报名字吗
Tell me,
说
what happened?
到底怎么了
Speak up.
说呀
It's about Tian Dongbao.
是田冬宝
What happened?
冬宝怎么了
Did the police catch him?
被警察抓了吗
Dongbao is no longer with us.
冬宝已经不在了
What...
什 什
do you mean
什么叫做
by "no longer with us"?
不在了
What does that mean?
什么叫做不在了
Yu said
小玉说
it's raining on the night before Dongbao
冬宝出事的前一天晚上
had an accident.
刚好下雨
He went to the warehouse to clean,
冬宝去仓库打扫卫生
worrying the goods
担心仓库的货
might get wet.
被雨给淋湿了
He went to
他就去仓库关窗户
close
然 然
the windows...
然后
he discovered smuggled military supplies
就发现了走私的军用品
and reported it..
他就去江海关举报了
Finding Minmin
我在冷库
in the cold storage,
找到珉敏的时候
I also saw Dongbao.
也看到了冬宝
He's about to become a father...
冬宝都要当爸爸了
Why would they do this to him?
他们为什么要这么对他
Why?
为什么
I'm here with some good news.
那我跟大家说个喜事儿
I'm going to be a dad!
我要当爹了
Propose a toast to Dongbao!
来 敬冬宝
To Dongbao!
敬冬宝 来
Come on,
来来来
congratulations!
恭喜啊恭喜
Congrats!
恭喜啊
Yu, you're going to be a mom!
小玉 你要当妈妈了
My name is Tian Dongbao!
我叫田冬宝
My family makes a living by raising chickens.
家里是在乡下养鸡
My dad didn't want me to do this.
我爹不让我养鸡
He said being a cop
他说当警察
pays better.
比养鸡赚得多
Miss Luo,
骆警官
you go ahead!
你先进去
You can't get in!
你们不能进去
Captain.
队长
It's okay, Captain.
没事儿 队长
Yuansheng!
向警官
I'm Dongbao.
田冬宝
Dongbao?
田警官
Yuansheng,
向警官
do you have time to come over
你今天晚上有没有时间
for dinner tonight?
来我家吃个饭
I'll invite everyone
我把四所的大家伙儿
from the Fourth Station.
都叫上